[
  {
    "question": "The Lathe of Heaven portrays Heather Lelache as",
    "a": "slow and dreamy",
    "b": "friendly and outgoing",
    "c": "impatient and easily frustrated",
    "d": "calm and collected",
    "e": "forgetful and absent-minded",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does Heather Lelache think George Orr has gone when she cannot find him at his apartment in Chapter 7?",
    "a": "to the river",
    "b": "to the airport",
    "c": "to his mother’s",
    "d": "to his workplace",
    "e": "to his cabin",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Heather Lelache think she is not suited to practice law?",
    "a": "She is too assertive.",
    "b": "She is not intelligent enough.",
    "c": "She loves the outdoors too much.",
    "d": "She lacks empathy for others.",
    "e": "She has a sneaky personality.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, Heather Lelache thinks that the moon symbolizes the",
    "a": "Female",
    "b": "Darkness",
    "c": "Mysterious",
    "d": "Unattainable",
    "e": "Lost",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the world of universal peace that George Orr dreams into existence, what is the Aliens' first act of aggression toward humanity?",
    "a": "the destruction of the Russian space platform",
    "b": "the burning of the suburbs",
    "c": "the murder of forty men in the Lunar Base",
    "d": "the bombing of Portland",
    "e": "the assassination of the American president",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Heather Lelache hear in the creek when she finds George Orr in Chapter 7?",
    "a": "“A faint and distant fear!”",
    "b": "“Eternal and uncompromising praise!”",
    "c": "“The slow and dauntless advance!”",
    "d": "“Joy from long ago!”",
    "e": "“The promise of rebirth!”",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Heather Lelache finds George Orr in Chapter 7, she thinks to herself that life is a(n)",
    "a": "thrilling adventure",
    "b": "boring routine",
    "c": "wild ride",
    "d": "joyous journey",
    "e": "incredible mess",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Heather Lelache finds George Orr in Chapter 7, why can he not relax?",
    "a": "He is being chased by someone.",
    "b": "He has had too much coffee.",
    "c": "He does not trust Heather.",
    "d": "He is afraid of the aliens.",
    "e": "He has not slept in days.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, what does Heather Lelache say happened to her husband?",
    "a": "He died in a car accident.",
    "b": "He was killed in the war.",
    "c": "He disappeared.",
    "d": "He suffered a heart attack.",
    "e": "",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, Heather Lelache wonders if there really are people who",
    "a": "love the universe",
    "b": "are not affected by fear",
    "c": "have no subconscious",
    "d": "resist evil",
    "e": "enjoy life",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, what does Heather Lelache tell George Orr to dream?",
    "a": "that he is cured",
    "b": "that they are married",
    "c": "that Dr. Haber is good",
    "d": "that there is no war",
    "e": "that the aliens have left",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, Heather Lelache proposes that George Orr should",
    "a": "change his sleeping schedule",
    "b": "let her hypnotize him",
    "c": "go on vacation",
    "d": "take tranquilizers",
    "e": "stop seeing Dr. Haber",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, Heather Lelache tells George Orr about the difficulties she has faced because she is",
    "a": "mixed race",
    "b": "too intelligent",
    "c": "unable to dream",
    "d": "a lawyer",
    "e": "unlikeable",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, what does George Orr say happened in April 1998?",
    "a": "The schools closed.",
    "b": "`The world ended.",
    "c": "A war erupted in the Middle East.",
    "d": "The was a massive epidemic.",
    "e": "The Constitution was rewritten.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, George Orr feels better when he dreams that he is",
    "a": "in prison",
    "b": "in a hospital",
    "c": "with Heather",
    "d": "at home",
    "e": "on the moon",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What, according to the narrator, is the function of a Senator from Oregon?",
    "a": "to preserve Oregon’s environment",
    "b": "to revolutionize government",
    "c": "to provide a good example",
    "d": "to expand the influence of state government",
    "e": "to drive all the other Senators mad",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What causes Haber to feel unnerved when he walks through the park after the alien attack in Chapter 7?",
    "a": "the empty expanse",
    "b": "the crowds",
    "c": "the volcanic eruption",
    "d": "the screams of animals",
    "e": "the power failure",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, Haber says that he MOST values",
    "a": "money",
    "b": "a stable job",
    "c": "close friendship",
    "d": "marriage",
    "e": "independence",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is Miss Crouch?",
    "a": "Haber’s assistant",
    "b": "the Institute’s caretaker",
    "c": "a love interest of George Orr’s",
    "d": "a radio host",
    "e": "a fellow researcher",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Orr arrives at the Institute after the alien landing in Chapter 7, he is with a woman whom Dr. Haber thinks is",
    "a": "a nurse",
    "b": "a random stranger",
    "c": "Orr’s wife",
    "d": "a fellow researcher",
    "e": "a disguised alien",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, What is the “idiotic mess” that Haber plans to fix with George’s dreams?",
    "a": "Portland’s traffic patterns",
    "b": "the Oregon Oneirological Institute’s loss of funding",
    "c": "Orr’s ability to change reality",
    "d": "the landing of the Aliens",
    "e": "the war in the Near East",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Haber feel when he finds out that George has had an “uncontrolled effective dream” in Chapter 7?",
    "a": "excited",
    "b": "pleased",
    "c": "angry",
    "d": "surprised",
    "e": "confused",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "After the Alien landing in Chapter 7, Haber notices that George has no",
    "a": "personal fear",
    "b": "sense of humor",
    "c": "feeling of pride",
    "d": "ability to dream",
    "e": "desire for company",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, what does Miss Lelache suggest after the explosion that blows out Haber’s office window?",
    "a": "gathering the emergency kit",
    "b": "turning on the radio",
    "c": "checking on Miss Crouch",
    "d": "pushing the desk against the door",
    "e": "going to the basement",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, Dr. Haber thinks of himself to be a(n)",
    "a": "family man",
    "b": "people person",
    "c": "social butterfly",
    "d": "independent thinker",
    "e": "lone wolf",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Dr. Haber sees an Alien ship outside his window in Chapter 7, he rushes to protect",
    "a": "the Augmentor",
    "b": "his files",
    "c": "his secretary",
    "d": "Heather Lelache",
    "e": "George Orr",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 7, Dr. Haber thinks the alien looks like a giant",
    "a": "elephant",
    "b": "cat",
    "c": "snake",
    "d": "lizard",
    "e": "turtle",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the armored figure say about self-destruction in Chapter 7?",
    "a": "It is a natural process.",
    "b": "It follows upon unfounded fear.",
    "c": "It has nothing to do with them.",
    "d": "It is a desirable outcome.",
    "e": "It is necessary for their survival.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What word does the Alien use to describe George Orr in Chapter 7?",
    "a": "iahklu’",
    "b": "quil’gorth",
    "c": "f’xalor",
    "d": "z’gryph~",
    "e": "nygrym~",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Orr suggest that Haber should call the government in Chapter 7?",
    "a": "to prepare for a full-scale invasion",
    "b": "to explain that the aliens are not attacking",
    "c": "to tell them to stay away from the area",
    "d": "to negotiate a peace treaty with the aliens",
    "e": "to request assistance from the military",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  }
]

